Guide to the Judson Memorial Church Archive MSS.094
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Accretion 2009 - Series C: General Archives
  - Subseries 14: Legal Materials
    - Grace House leases, Oxley, 1976 (Box .09.21, Folder 47)
    - Grace House leases, Sherman, 1979-1985 (Box .09.21, Folder 48)
    - Meet the Composer Contract - Paul Knopf, 2 Feb 1981 (Box .09.21, Folder 49)
    - Grace House - NYC property assessment, 1981-1994 (Box .09.21, Folder 50)
    - Grace House leases, Crohn sublet agreement, 1983 (Box .09.21, Folder 51)
    - Grace House, Crohn litigation, 1985 (Box .09.21, Folder 52)
    - Grace House, NYC Department of Finance owner's identification form, 1986 (Box .09.21, Folder 53)
    - Grace House leases, Dana & Martha Beaton, 1986 (Box .09.21, Folder 54)
    - NYC property tax exemption, 1987-1998 (Box .09.21, Folder 55)
    - NYS Department of Labor industry verification statement, 1993 (Box .09.21, Folder 56)
    - NYC Finance notice of assessment, 1993-1999 (Box .09.21, Folder 57)
    - Grace House leases, Trincia, 1994-1998 (Box .09.21, Folder 58)
    - Grace House & Judson House - NYC property registration receipt, 1996, 1998, 1999 (Box .09.21, Folder 59)
  - Subseries 15: Affiliations
    - Affiliated Baptist City Societies, 1971 (Box .09.21, Folder 60)
    - American Baptist Churches of Metro NY - delegates and meetings, 1973-1975 (Box .09.21, Folder 61)
    - American Baptist Convetion of Metro NY - annual report, 1976-1985 (Box .09.21, Folder 62)
    - American Baptist Ministers and Missionaries Benefit Board, awards, 1977-1990 (Box .09.21, Folder 63)
    - American Baptist Churches of Metro NY - annual reports, 1981-1992 (Box .09.21, Folder 64)
    - American Baptists - Retired Ministers & Missionaries Offering (ROMO), 1990-1991 (Box .09.21, Folder 65)
    - UCC - local church yearbook report, 1979-1993 (Box .09.21, Folder 66)
    - UCC - Open & Affirming, 1990-1995 (Box .09.21, Folder 67)
    - UCC - annual report, 1994 (Box .09.21, Folder 68)
    - UCC - offering, 1994 (Box .09.21, Folder 69)
  - Subseries 16: Space Use
    - Space Use, 1971-1973 (Box .09.21, Folder 70)
    - Space Use - Public meetings at Judson, 1979-1982 (Box .09.21, Folder 71)
    - Space Use, 1988-1989 (Box .09.21, Folder 72)
    - Space Use, thank you notes, letters of understanding, 1990-1991 (Box .09.21, Folder 73)
    - Fluxus - 30th anniversary performances, 1991 (Box .09.21, Folder 74)
    - Greenwich Village Oral History Project exhibition, 1991 (Box .09.21, Folder 75)
    - Greenwich Village Society for Historic Preservation walking tour: "Old Churches of Greenwich Village", 1991 (Box .09.21, Folder 76)
    - Franklin Furnace in Exile, 1991 (Box .09.21, Folder 77)
    - Space Use - reports/requests, 1992 (Box .09.21, Folder 78)
    - Walt Whitman celebration, 1992 (Box .09.21, Folder 79)
    - Space Use - reports/requests, 1993-1994 (Box .09.21, Folder 80)
    - "Art and Liberation" with Landsbergis piano recital, 1994 (Box .09.21, Folder 81)
    - Opelika Pictures - "Family Name," Macky Alston, 1994-1996 (Box .09.21, Folder 82)
    - Space Use requests, 1995 (Box .09.21, Folder 83)
    - Big Red Productions - "Mother's Day", 1995 (Box .09.22, Folder 1)
    - Space Use requests, 1996 (Box .09.22, Folder 2)
    - Space Use requests, 1997 (Box .09.22, Folder 3)
    - Partners for Sacred Spaces, 1997 (Box .09.22, Folder 4)
    - Mac Wellman Festival - play reading, 1997 (Box .09.22, Folder 5)
    - Peculiar Works Project - Big Art in Small Spaces, 1997 (Box .09.22, Folder 6)
    - Peculiar Works Project - "3 Christs", 1997-1998 (Box .09.22, Folder 7)
    - International Sex Workers Foundation, 1997-1998 (Box .09.22, Folder 8)
    - Space Use Reports - 1 of 2, 1996-1998 (Box .09.22, Folder 9)
    - Space Use Reports - 2 of 2, 1996-1998 (Box .09.22, Folder 10)
    - Space Use - thank you notes, 1998 (Box .09.22, Folder 11)
    - World Dance Alliance - Patricia A. Rowe tribute, 1998 (Box .09.22, Folder 12)
    - Staged reading - "Virgin" by Dina Von Zweck, 1998 (Box .09.22, Folder 13)
    - Sightlines Theater Company, 1998 (Box .09.22, Folder 14)
    - HIV Arts Alliance, 1998-1999 (Box .09.22, Folder 15)
    - Space Use Policy, 1998-2000 (Box .09.22, Folder 16)
    - Space Use, 1999 (Box .09.22, Folder 17)
    - Bill Bradley for President, rally at Judson, 2000 (Box .09.22, Folder 18)
    - Public meetings at Judson, 2000 (Box .09.22, Folder 19)
    - Space Use, 2000 (Box .09.22, Folder 20)
- Accretion 2009 - Series F: Early Church History
  - Mr. and Mrs. Edmund Severn, special music, short sermon by Edward Judson, flier, undated (Box .09.22, Folder 21)
  - Ledger of Judson Board Minutes, 1906-1910 (Box .09.22, Folder 22)
- Accretion 2009 - Series G: Media
  All media series are divided by media type and into two subseries: "Access Copies" and "Originals."
  - Subseries 1: Audiocassettes
    Audiocassettes have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
    - Judson Poets' Theatre Panel Discussion, 21 Apr 1999; cuid7058 (Box .09.28, Object ID: 094.0399)
      Transcripts of interviws available in Accretion 2009 Box 2, Folders 53-56.
    - Window Dedication, 20 Oct 1997; cuid7059 (Box .09.28, Object ID: 094.0400)
      See Box 6, folder 6 for accompanying materials.
  - Subseries 2: Audio Reels
    - Test Tone, undated; cuid7060 (Box .09.28, Object ID: 094.0401)
      Format: 1/4 in. reel to reel
    - Production tapes - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, 1 of 4, 10 Nov 1979; cuid7061 (Box .09.23, Object ID: 094.0402)
      Format: 2 in. reel to reel
    - Production tapes - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, 2 of 4, 10 Nov 1979; cuid7062 (Box .09.23, Object ID: 094.0403)
    - Production tapes - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, 3 of 4, 10 Nov 1979; cuid7063 (Box .09.24, Object ID: 094.0404)
    - Production tapes - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, 10 Nov 1979; cuid7064 (Box .09.24, Object ID: 094.0405)
    - Master reel - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, 1 of 4, 16 Nov 1979; cuid7065 (Box .09.28, Object ID: 094.0406)
      Format: 1/4 in reel to reel
    - Master reel - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, 2 of 4, 16 Nov 1979; cuid7066 (Box .09.28, Object ID: 094.0407)
    - Master reel - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, 3 of 4, 16 Nov 1979; cuid7067 (Box .09.28, Object ID: 094.0408)
    - Master reel - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, 4 of 4, 16 Nov 1979; cuid7068 (Box .09.28, Object ID: 094.0409)
  - Subseries 3: Videorecordings
    Arrangement Note
    Release forms for oral history videotapes can be found in Accretion 2009, Series A, Sub 1, Box 2, Folder 11A.
    - Workfare Campaign of Resistance - VHS tape of "20/20" with Laarman interview, 9 Mar 1998; ID: 094.0410 (Box .09.28, Media ID: 094.0410)
      Format: VHS
    - Judson Church #1 - Howard Moody 2/6/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0411 (Case 094.0411, Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0411)
      Access DVD available.
    - Judson #2 - Howard Moody 2/6/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0412 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0412, Case 094.0412)
    - Sue Harwig Interviewed by Ed Powers; Shot by AliceElliott 3/18/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0413 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0413, Case 094.0413)
    - Art Levin 1 of 2 - 4/1/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0414 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0414, Case 094.0414)
    - Art Levin 2 of 2 - 4/1/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0415 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0415, Case 094.0415)
    - George Todd #1 - 4/29/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0416 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0416, Case 094.0416)
    - George Todd #2 - 4/29/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0417 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0417, Case 094.0417)
    - Larry Kornfeld #1 - 8/4/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0418 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0418, Case 094.0418)
    - Larry Kornfeld #2 - 8/4/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0419 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0419, Case 094.0419)
    - Al Carmines Interview #1 of 3 (CB at end) - 9/3/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0420 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0420, Case 094.0420)
    - Al Carmines Interview #2 of 3 - 9/3/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0421 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0421, Case 094.0421)
    - Al Carmines Interview #3 of 3 - 9/3/98, [1998]; ID: 094.0422 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0422, Case 094.0422)
    - Grace Goodman #1 - 1/30/00, [2000]; ID: 094.0423 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0423, Case 094.0423)
    - Grace Goodman #2 - 1/30/00, [2000]; ID: 094.0424 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0424, Case 094.0424)
    - Judson Church #1: Essie Borden, Lee Guilliatt 3/25/00, [2000]; ID: 094.0425 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0425, Case 094.0425)
    - Judson Church #2: Essie Borden, Lee Guilliatt 3/25/00, [2000]; ID: 094.0426 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0426, Case 094.0426)
    - People's Flag Show - Reel #1, 1970; ID: 094.0441 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0441, Case 094.0441)
    - People's Flag Show - Reel #2, 1970; ID: 094.0442 (Box .09.27, Media ID: 094.0442, Case 094.0442)
  - Subseries 6: Vinyl Recordings - LP, 12 in.
    Documentation of test pressings available in Accretion 2009 - Series C: Subseries 8, box 13, folder 22.
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings," by Al Carmines, sides 1 and 4, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
      Format: Sound Disc: Analog, 33 1/3 rpm; 12 in.
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings," by Al Carmines, sides 1 and 4, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings," by Al Carmines, sides 1 and 4, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings," by Al Carmines, sides 1 and 4, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings," by Al Carmines, sides 1 and 4, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, sides 2 and 3, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, sides 2 and 3, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, sides 2 and 3, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, sides 2 and 3, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, sides 2 and 3, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
    - Test Pressing - "Christmas Rappings" by Al Carmines, sides unidentified, 28 Nov 1979 (Box .09.25)
- OVERSIZE Series A: Arts
  - Subseries 1: Arts-General
    - Score to "Sing, Mars, of Peace" by Robert Russell/Book of Mozart Scores, undated (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - The Found Object Concert-Photographs, undated (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Certificate Awarding Judson Memorial Church for Support of Avant-Garde Art. Issued by the Borough of Manhattan, 1991 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Posters, undated (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - First New York Theater Rally, May, 1965 (Folder 1 Left)
      2 original posters made with the cyanotype process for the New York Theater Rally, featuring works and performances by Trisha Brown, Lucinda Childs, Claes Oldenberg, Steve Paxton, Yvonne Rainer, Robert Rauschenberg, Robert Whitman and others.
      11x14 black and white photograph of participants.
  - Subseries 2: Judson Dance Theater Posters
    - Posters, 1964-69, 1964-1969 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 3: Judson Poets' Theater
    - Scores, 1964-65, 1964-1965 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Posters (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Asphodel/What Happened?-Photograph, 9/27/1963 (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - Cabaret Series Artwork, undated (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Judson Revivals-Photographs, May 22-June 5, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - San Francisco Burning-Photographs, Jan. 1-9, 13-16, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Dr. Faustus Lights the Lights-Program Master, Oct. 26-29, Nov. 2-5, 9-12, 16-19, 1979 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified Photograph of Poets' Theater Performance, undated (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4: Judson Gallery
    - Posters, etc. 1962-68, 1962-1968 (Box 93, Folder 4)
- OVERSIZE Series B: Building
  - Subseries 1: Judson Memorial Church Building
    - Long Range Planning Committee-Maps of the Washington Square Park Area, undated (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Church Photographs by Peter Moore, 1962-63, 1962-1963 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Architectural plans (Folder 1, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Centennial Renovations
    - La Farge Stained-Glass Windows/Front Entryway Roof/Drainage/Interior Marble, 1991-93, 1991-1993 (Box 93, Folder 7)
- OVERSIZE FLAT Series B: Building
- OVERSIZE Series C: General Archives - Ledgers
  - Subseries 3: Membership
    - Series C, Subseries 4: Financial Records
      - Weekly Cash Records, 1893-1897 (Box 91)
      - Cash Book Ledger, 1894-1909 (Box 88)
      - Treasurer's Records, 1897-1900 (Box 91)
      - Treasurer's Correspondence (tissue carbons), 1898-1900 (Box 88)
      - Treasurer's Correspondence (tissue carbons), 1900-1903 (Box 88)
      - Cash Book No. 4, 1900-1906 (Box 90)
      - Treasurer's Correspondence (tissue carbons), 1903-1906 (Box 88)
      - Treasurer's Correspondence (tissue carbons), 1906-1908 (Box 88)
      - Cash Book No. 5, 1906-1912 (Box 89)
      - Treasurer's Correspondence (tissue carbons), 1908-1910 (Box 88, Folder data_value_missing_90f3a3550a3b495224e64d3880e6f9f8)
      - Judson Memorial Fund Committee (receipts of pledges), 1918 (Box 90)
    - Membership Pledges, 1881-1983 (Box 90)
    - Attendance Records at Various Programs/Visitation Records, 1904-1920 (Box 88)
- OVERSIZE Series C: General Archives
  - Subseries 4: Financial Information
    - Pledge Drive, 11-12, 1982 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 6: Worship Materials
    - Bulletin Originals and Metal Plates, undated (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 8: Minister-Generated Materials
    - Carmines 10th Anniversary Celebration, 1972/Moody 20 Years at Judson Church Celebration, 1977, 1972, 1977 (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Carmines-Photographs, undated (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - Moody-"Redefining Health Care" from Christianity and Crisis-Plate Negatives, 10/1975 (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Moody-Photographs, undated (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 9: Correspondence
    - Carmines-General, 1972 (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 10: Community/ Social Action Programs
    - AIDS Task Force-Needle Exchange Article, undated (Box 93, Folder 15)
    - Community Center-Photographs, undated (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 11: Special Events
    - March in Washington-Photographs, undated (Box 93, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 13: Photographs
    - Children at Judson Memorial Church [c. 1915], Misc. Events (Box 93, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 15: Affiliations
    - The American Baptist Churches-Certificate of Appreciation, 1987 (Box 93, Folder 19)
- OVERSIZE Series E: Books
  - Migdoll, Herbert (with forward by Robert Joffrey). Dancers Dancing. Harry N. Abrams Publishing, New York, 1978 (Box 93, Folder 20)
- OVERSIZE Series F: Early Church History - Ledgers
  - Subseries 1: Berean Church
    - Berean Baptist Church Minutes (with inserts), 1882-1897 (Box 89)
- Accretion 2001 - OVERSIZE Series C: General Archives
  - Subseries 4: Financial Information
    - Financial Ledgers - 1968- 1976 (Box 86)
    - Financial Ledgers - 1977- 1990 (Box 87)
- Accretion 2009 - OVERSIZE Series A: Arts
  - Subseries 2: Judson Dance Theater
    - Lucinda Childs Dance Company 25th Anniversary (Box .09.26, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3: Judson Poet's Theater
    - Judson Poets' Theater - photograph of "Joan", [1971 or '72] (Box .09.26, Folder 2)
    - Judson Poets' Theater - photograph of recording session (Box .09.26, Folder 3)
- Accretion 2009 - OVERSIZE Series C: General Archives
  - Subseries 11: Special Events
    - Events - Howard Moody 25th Anniversary Celebration, 1977 (Box .09.26, Folder 4)
- Accretion 2009 - OVERSIZE series D: Scrapbooks and Yearbooks
  - Judson Health Center scrapbooks of clippings and photocopies, ca. 2000s (Box 92, Folder 11)
- Unprocessed Materials (Box 109)